(
"ai_sub_version": "3.0.3",
"generated_at": "2026-07-03T00:11:47.421818",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 16,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あ、あ、あ、皆様おー！
Ah, ah, ah, everyone, hello!
いいね！コメント元気だね。
Nice! You're so energetic in the comments.
本日は風真いろは生誕ライブ2026『Wind Trails』にご来場くださいまして、誠に...
Thank you very much indeed for coming to Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026 "Wind Trails" today...
...ありがとうございます！
...thank you so much!
いぇーい！
Yay!
開演に先立ちまして、皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
Prior to the start of the performance, I would like to make some requests and announcements.
開演中、カメラやスマートフォンなどは、えー、電源切られると見れなくなって困るので、電源は切らず、
During the show, if you turn off your cameras or smartphones, you won't be able to watch, so please don't turn them off.
写真撮影などね、大量にしていただき、当配信のハッシュタグ『#風真いろは生誕ライブ2026』で、SNSに大量に画像ポストしてください！
Instead, please take lots of screenshots and post them on SNS with the stream hashtag #KazamaIrohaBirthdayLive2026!
目指せ、Xトレンド1位！よろしくお願いいたします！
Let's aim for the #1 trending topic on X! I appreciate your support!
あ、あの、でもスマホね、いっぱい写真撮ったりすると充電なくなっちゃいそうなんで、スマホで見てる勢は充電しっかりしてくださいね！
Oh, but if you take too many photos, your phone might run out of battery, so those watching on phones, make sure they're fully charged!
はい、そしてその2！激しく頭を振る、えー、激しくペンライトを振る、などはですね、
Alright, and part two! Shaking your head violently, or, ah, waving your penlight violently...
あの、あなた様のご自宅を破壊する危険性がございますので。あの、破壊されてもですね、こちらは責任一切負えませんので、お気をつけください。ダメだよ、みんな！
...has the risk of destroying your home. And even if it gets destroyed, we can't take any responsibility, so please be careful. No doing that, everyone!
あ、そしてあと、もう1個、その3！今からハヤシライスを準備しようとしてる奴は、間に合わないからやめな。
Oh, and one more thing, part three! Anyone trying to make Hayashi rice right now, you won't make it in time, so don't do it.
絶対間に合わないから！
You definitely won't make it in time!
まあね、何か食べたり飲んだりしながら、ぜひね、ゆっくり楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです！
Well, I hope you have a great, relaxing time while eating or drinking something!
それでは、もうそろそろ始まるので、
Well then, it's about to start very soon, so...
今しばらくお待ちください。最後まで見てねー！
...please wait just a little longer. Make sure to watch until the very end!
風真いろは生誕ライブ2026、いくよー！
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026, let's go!
いっせーので鳴り響いたスタートの合図
With a sign of "ready, set, go," the starting signal rang out
なぞった線で結んだ世界 色付けていく
Coloring the world connected by the traced lines
ここから
From here
物心がついた頃 すでにここにあった
By the time I was old enough to understand, it was already here
僕じゃない誰かの記憶は 夕日と共に よみがえる
Someone else's memories, not mine, rise up again with the setting sun
古ぼけた絵本を取り出して
Taking out a worn-out picture book,
落書きの中に1つの答えを見つけた
I found one answer inside the scribbles
自分の価値に目を疑って どこまでだって堕ちていけるの
Doubting my own worth, wondering how far down I can fall
どこか遠くに消えてしまいたい こんな世界じゃ僕は要らない
Wishing I could disappear somewhere far away, I'm not needed in a world like this
カウントダウンは始まっているよ
The countdown has already begun
いっせーので声を上げて 聞こえてくるんだ
Raise your voice with "ready, set, go," I can hear it coming
自分の影の長さに気づく もうこんな時間だ
Noticing the length of my shadow, it's already this late
一等星が顔を出した 届きそうで手を伸ばした
The brightest star showed its face, I stretched out my hand as if I could reach it
次は僕に ついてきなよ どんな暗闇でも
Next, follow me, no matter how dark it gets
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet.
幕は上がりだした
The curtain has begun to rise
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet.
色付けていく ここから
Coloring it in, starting from here
10年後も僕らは すれ違いばかりで
Even ten years later, we keep passing each other by
幻想に想いを馳せては 戻れない そう思い込んだ
Letting my thoughts drift to illusions, thinking we can never go back
くたびれた心に追い打ちを
Adding further blows to a worn-out heart,
あの頃と変わらない夕日も 何とも思わない
Even the setting sun, unchanged from back then, moves me no longer
自分を信じ歩いていければ どこまでだって上れるのにな
If only I could believe in myself and keep walking, I could climb to any height
カットを跨ぐその空白に 大切なもの見落としている
In the blank spaces between cuts, I am overlooking what's truly precious
見つけられないと 泣き喚く君へ
To you, crying out that you cannot find it
いっせーので声を上げて 聞こえてくるんだ
Raise your voice with "ready, set, go," I can hear it coming
自分の影の長さに気づく もうこんな時間だ
Noticing the length of my shadow, it's already this late
一等星で駆け抜ける君 くっついていただけの僕でも
Even for me, who was just clinging to you as you rushed like a first-magnitude star
君前を走れるから こんな頼りない僕でも
I can still run in front of you, even if I'm this unreliable
宝箱はホコリをかぶったまま 無くした
The treasure chest was lost while covered in dust
鍵はずっと君のポケットの中にあった
The key was always inside your pocket
散らばっていた全てが 今1つに重なる
Everything that was scattered is now overlapping into one
手を取り始めよう 僕たちの物語
Let's hold hands and begin our story
一度は要らないと思った
Once, I thought I didn't need it
今なら胸を張れる気がしたんだ
But now, I feel like I can stand proud
愛おしくて
So precious,
掛け声はいつも
the call is always...
いっせーので声を上げて
Raise your voice with "ready, set, go!"
いっせーので声を上げて 聞こえてくるんだ
Raise your voice with "ready, set, go," I can hear it coming
自分の影の長さに気づく もうこんな時間だ
Noticing the length of my shadow, it's already this late
一等星が顔を出した 届きそうで手を伸ばした
The brightest star showed its face, I stretched out my hand as if I could reach it
次は僕に ついてきなよ どんな暗闇でも
Next, follow me, no matter how dark it gets
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet.
泣きじゃくった声で
With a sobbing voice
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet.
笑う君が見えた
I saw you smiling
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet.
幕は上がりだした
The curtain has begun to rise
もういいかい？
Are you ready?
もういいよ
I'm ready
色付けていく ここから
Coloring it in, starting from here
はい！ということで
Alright! And with that...
始まりましたー！
It has begun!
風真いろは生誕ライブ2026
Kazamai Iroha Birthday Live 2026!
スタート！みんな、こんばんはー！
Start! Good evening, everyone!
見えてるー？はい、ということで本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
Are you watching? Okay, so here's today's hashtag!
こちらね、みんな、いっぱいポストしていっぱいかっこいいとこ撮ってくださいね。
Please post a lot with this, and take lots of cool screenshots.
頼むよ！この風真いろはがイケメンであることを世の中に知らしめられるのは、
I'm counting on you! Because you are the only ones...
お前たちだけ、お前たちだけなので。よろしくお願いします！
...who can show the world how cool I am. I'm counting on you!
はい、そして今回のライブ、タイトルがついております。
Yes, and this live show has a title.
『Wind Trails』というね、タイトルがついておりますが、
It's titled "Wind Trails".
まあ、そのまんま訳して結構お気づきの方も多かったんですが、
If you translate it literally, many of you probably already guessed...
まあ「風の軌跡」というね、あの意味を込めて付けさせていただき、
...but I named it with the meaning of "Traces of the Wind"...
今回ライブ色々、頑張って、考えさせていただきました。
and worked hard to put this concert together.
なのでね、最後まで楽しんでいただけると嬉しいです！
So I hope you'll enjoy it until the end!
そして、1曲目！「かくれんぼ」、歌わせていただきました！
And for the first song, I sang "Kakurenbo"!
どうだったかなー？
How was it?
はい、そして、今日室内ライブだと思ったでしょ？
You probably thought today's concert was indoors, right?
違うー！
Nope!
曲中にドームが開きましたー！
The dome opened during the song!
イェーイ！すごーい！
Yay! Amazing!
やっぱね、なかなか現地ライブって、できてもさ、青空の下でなかなか歌ってることってないので、
After all, even when we can do live concerts, we rarely get to sing under the blue sky.
いつか俺たちとお前たちの次元が交わって、空の下で歌えるような世界が来るかもしれないけど、
Maybe one day our dimensions will merge and we can sing under the sky...
やってみたくてね。今回は空の下で歌うっていうこの演出をやらせていただきましたー！
...but I really wanted to try it, so we did this performance today!
めっちゃいいでしょ？
It's pretty great, right?
ステージもめっちゃかっこいいんで！
The stage is super cool too!
今日はね、多分いっぱい見る機会あると思いますが、ゆっくり隅から隅まで、
You'll have plenty of chances to see it today, so look closely from corner to corner.
アーカイブでもきっといると思うんで、本当に色んな細部こだわってるので、細かく見てくださいねー！
I paid attention to all the small details, so even in the archive, please look closely!
ということで、お水飲んでいいですかね？
So, may I have some water?
お水を、うっ！やめろ！俺の頭を...
Water... Ow! Stop! My head...
うっ！やめっ！あ、やめっ...
Ow! Stop! Ah, stop...
頭をいじくり回されて、ヘッドセットになりました。
After having my head messed with, now I have a headset on.
そして水が、お水、用意してくれたんだよね。みんなに見える水！
And they prepared some water for me. Water that everyone can see!
うまい！うますぎる！
Good! This is too good!
この、この振りはちょっと怒られそうだからもうできないけど、うますぎる！
I might get yelled at for this pose so I can't do it again, but it's so good!
うまいなー。
So good.
これで、あと一時間やるか。そういうわけにはいかないんで、一回ね、水は返して。
Should we do another hour of this? We can't do that, so let me put the water back.
それじゃあ、水分補給もさせてもらって、
Alright, now that I've hydrated...
息も整ったんじゃない？
And caught my breath...
はい、次の曲早速いってみたいと思います！
Yes, let's head straight into the next song!
それでは、次の曲聞いてください。
Now, please listen to the next song.
「白線」
"Hakusen"
澄み渡った空に白線
A white line in the clear sky
あの地平を超えて
Beyond that horizon
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
もっと！はい！はい！
More! Hey! Hey!
始まりはちょっと軽い期待で
Starting with a light expectation
その欠片そっとポケットしまって
Putting the fragment gently into my pocket
屋上 遠い空の向こうを見ていた
Looking at the far side of the sky from the rooftop
この足でどこに行けるかなんて
I don't know where I can go with these feet
わかってないけどわかってるんだ防ぐため
But I know, I understand
白昼 淡い月に手を伸ばした
Reaching my hand out to the pale moon in the daylight
かすれたエコーでも答えはもう
Even if it's a faint echo, the answer
はじめからちゃんと持っていたんだよ
I've had it with me from the start
メイビーこの想いは
Maybe this feeling
マスビー熱を増して
Must be, increasing the heat
ほらね、飛べるんだ
Look, I can fly
もっと高く高くまで
Higher and higher
羽ばたいてみたい
I want to try spreading my wings
今日に未来色の軌道描いて
Drawing a future-colored trajectory to today
地平の先まで
To the edge of the horizon
届かない歌はない
There is no song that cannot reach
迷いはいらない
I don't need to hesitate
どんな世界も瞬間も揺るがない
Neither any world nor any moment will shake
アイが在るから
Because love is there
澄み渡った空に白線
A white line in the clear sky
繋がったのアンビバレント
Connected, ambivalent
でも声はもう気づいてる
But my voice is already aware
もっと高く高く高く飛んでいける！
Higher, higher, higher, I can fly!
紡いでたら「一途」に変わったよ
When spun, it turned into "earnest devotion".
あたりさわりない
Safe and harmless...
言葉じゃ 覆いきれないほどのマイ ワールド
words can't cover my entire world.
明日で呼ぶ声の持ち主は
The owner of the voice calling out in tomorrow
他でもないこの心だった
was none other than this heart of mine.
見えないって言っているその言葉も
Even those words saying you can't see it,
「言葉」だと足りないだけ
simply aren't enough if they're just "words".
掴んだもの 落としたもの
What I grasped, what I dropped,
転んだって立って見えた視界から
from the view I saw when I stood up after falling...
ロックユー！ 解き放って
Rock you! Release it!
フォーユー！ 響きだして
For you! Resonate!
景色変えてゆく
The scenery is changing...
まだ遠く 遠くまで 広がった空に
Towards the sky that has spread further and further away,
やっと踏み出すこの一歩なんて ちっぽけだけど
finally taking this step forward, though it's so small.
届かない場所へと 続いていく
It continues on to unreachable places...
どんな風に雨に消えない 白線を描く
Drawing a white line that won't fade in any wind or rain.
もっと高く 高くまで 羽ばたいていたい
I want to soar higher and higher,
そして彼方色で繋ぐ 地平で待ってて
and then wait for me at the horizon, connected with the color of beyond.
もう願いに嘘はない ここが好き！
There are no more lies in my wishes. I love it here!
どんな世界も瞬間も輝く アイが在るから
Every world and every moment shines because love is here.
今はただ想うこと言えばいい 「愛しているよ！」
Now, all I need to do is speak my thoughts: "I love you!"
澄み渡った空に白線
A white line in the clear sky,
不安と期待がアンビバレント
anxiety and anticipation are ambivalent.
でも君はもう気づいてる
But you've already noticed,
もっと高く高く高く飛んでいける
we can fly higher, higher, and higher!
もっと
More...
鏡よ 教えて
Mirror, mirror, tell me,
私の証は
where is my proof of existence?
どこにあるのだろう
Where could it be?
わからない わからないよ
I don't know, I just don't know.
周りと比べたってさ 虚しくなるだけ
Comparing myself to others only makes me feel empty,
あのノイズが海鳴りのように涙を奪う
that noise robs me of my tears like the roaring of the sea.
切り取った風景を道標にしよう
Let's make this captured scenery our guidepost.
そうだ 傷ついた感情も 連れて行くから
Yes, because I'll bring even my hurt feelings along with me.
そっと響くカンパネラ 新しい未来を感じてる
A softly resonating Campanella, I'm feeling a new future.
怖くたって 進むしかないでしょう
Even if I'm scared, there's no choice but to move forward, right?
遠くまで
All the way into the distance!
もっと もっと 届けこの祈りよ 光となれ
More, more! Reach out, my prayer, and become light!
もっと もっと 少しずつでもいい 私という答えを
More, more! Even if it's little by little, the answer that is myself...
もっと もっと
More... more...
夜空よ 教えて
Night sky, tell me,
私の証は
will my proof of existence
輝けるのかな
be able to shine?
見つけたい 見つけたいよ
I want to find it, I really want to find it.
誰かの決めたレッテルは 苦しくなるだけ
The labels decided by others only make it painful,
ねえ ノイズも力に変えるよ 心に誓う
hey, I'll turn even the noise into strength, I swear to my heart.
錆びついた運命の歯車を回そう
Let's turn the rusted gears of fate.
ほら 着飾った感情は 脱ぎ捨てるから
Look, because I'll throw off these dressed-up emotions.
そっと紡ぐシンフォニア 叶えたい願いを信じてる
A softly spun Symphonia, I believe in the wish I want to fulfill.
胸を張って 歌うしかないでしょう 全力で
With my chest held high, there's no choice but to sing, with all my might!
もっと もっと やがて希望の歌に変わる日まで
More, more! Until the day it eventually turns into a song of hope,
もっと もっと 悩みながらでいい 全てが宝物
more, more! It's okay to worry, because everything is a treasure.
いつの日か この声を 受け取ってくれたなら
If one day, you receive this voice of mine...
この言葉を君に もう大丈夫 ひとりじゃない
These words are for you: "It's okay, you're not alone anymore."
強い想いを
With strong feelings...
繋ぐよ
We'll connect them!
一歩踏み出してみた 優しく世界は微笑む
I tried taking a step forward, and the world gently smiles.
高鳴る気持ちに 身を任せて さあ行こう保存
Entrusting myself to this racing heart, let's go!
響くカンパネラ...
The resounding campanella...
新しい未来を感じてる
I can feel a new future.
コンパクトにまとまって
Packing light,
進むしかないでしょう
we have no choice but to move forward, right?
遠くまで
To somewhere far away...
もっと もっと
More, more!
届けこの祈りよ光となれ
Reach out, this prayer, and become light!
もっと もっと
More, more...
少しずつでもいい私という答えを
Even if it's little by little, show me the answer that is myself!
もっと もっと もっと
More, more, more!
雨とペトラ
[Title: Rain and Petra]
誰かが言った いつか空は 灰になって落ちるって
Someone said that one day the sky will turn to ash and fall.
妄想の世の中で 日々を喰らっている
In this world of delusions, I am devouring my days.
境界線を引いてしまうのも 共感性のせいにして
Blaming even drawing a boundary line on empathy,
街の灯の海で 居場所を探している
I'm searching for a place to belong in the sea of city lights.
何処へ行くにも この足は 退屈に染まって動かない
No matter where I go, these feet are stained with boredom and won't move.
少しだけ先の
I just want to see
景色が見たいだけなのにな
the scenery just a little bit ahead, and yet...
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったらきっと
If it rains, if it rains, surely
頬を濡らしてしまう
it will wet my cheeks.
枯れてしまった色ですら 愛しくなるのに
Even though withered colors would become dear to me,
目を瞑ったら 目を瞑ったらもっと
if I close my eyes, if I close my eyes, even more
遠く霞んでしまう
will fade far away into a haze.
うるさくなった雨の音 笑い飛ばしてくれ
Please laugh away the sound of the rain that has grown loud.
誰かが言った いつか溜息は
Someone said that one day sighs
夜に化けて歌を歌う
will turn into the night and sing songs.
妄想の世の中で 日々を喰らっている
In this world of delusions, I am devouring my days.
優しい嘘を なぞったせいで
Because I traced a gentle lie,
離れる声に気付かない
I don't notice the voice growing distant.
溶けた月が 足元に落ちて
The melted moon falls to my feet,
静かに揺れていた
quietly swaying.
夜が降ったら 夜が降ったらきっと
If night falls, if night falls, surely
今日を責めてしまう
I will blame today.
満たされない日々の底で 夢を見ているだけ
Just dreaming at the bottom of these unfulfilled days.
目を逸らしても 目を逸らしてもずっと
Even if I look away, even if I look away, forever
後悔と愛の隙間
in the gap between regret and love...
取り残されてしまう前に 手を伸ばしてくれ
Before I get left behind, reach out your hand to me.
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったらきっと
If it rains, if it rains, surely...
湿るアスファルト背に写して 俯いた
Reflecting the damp asphalt on my back, I looked down.
独りぼっちでまた 明日に期待をして
All alone, looking forward to tomorrow again.
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったらきっと
If it rains, if it rains, surely
頬を濡らしてしまう
it will wet my cheeks.
枯れてしまった色ですら 愛しくなるのに
Even though withered colors would become dear to me,
目を瞑ったら 目を瞑ったらもっと
if I close my eyes, if I close my eyes, even more
遠く霞んでしまう
will fade far away into a haze.
うるさくなった雨の音 笑い飛ばしてくれ
Please laugh away the sound of the rain that has grown loud.
群青讃歌
[Title: Ultramarine Anthem]
繋がっていたいって 信じられる言葉
Words that make me believe I want to be connected
だってもう昨日の僕らにおさらば
Because we have already bid farewell to the us of yesterday
青い春を過ごした 遠い稲妻
Faraway lightning bolt that passed through the blue spring
さっと泣いて 前だけを向けたら
If I could just cry and look straight ahead
きっとどんなに楽になれていたろうな
I wonder how much easier things would have become
この心を揺らした 一縷の望みは
A single glimmer of hope that shook my heart
ないものねだりは辞めた 未完成人間
I stopped asking for things I didn't have, I'm an incomplete human
素晴らしき世界だけが
Only a wonderful world...
答えを握ってる
...holds the answer
諦めてしまうほど この先沢山の
Enough to make me want to give up, so many...
後悔が君を待ってるけど
...regrets await you in the future, but...
もうない 迷いはしないよ
...no more, I won't hesitate anymore
この傷も愛しく 思えてしまうほど
Enough to make even these wounds seem dear
重ねてしまうよ 不格好なまんまでいいから
I'll pile them up, it's fine to stay just as I am, imperfect
走れ その歩幅で
Run, with that stride,
走れ 声轟かせてくれ
Run, let your voice roar!
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて
Embracing expectations and anxieties in equal measure
君と今を紡ぐ未来照らして
Illuminating the future I weave with you in the present
顔も名前も知らない僕たちが
We, who don't know each other's faces or names
たった1つの音をかき鳴らす
Are striking a single sound together
いたずらみたいな奇跡のような刹那
In this moment that feels like a miracle, like a prank
あっという間に流れる時が
Time flows by in the blink of an eye
ありのままで在り続ける怖さが
The fear of continuing to exist just as I am
生まれついた時から
From the moment I was born,
忌み子 鬼の子として
as an unwanted child, as a demon child,
その身に余る 罰を受けた
I received punishment beyond what my body could bear.
悲しい事は 何も無いけど
There wasn't really anything sad about it,
夕焼け小焼け 手を引かれてさ
but at sunset, my hand was pulled.
知らない 知らない 僕は何も知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything,
叱られた後のやさしさも
even the kindness after being scolded,
雨上がりの手の温もりも
even the warmth of a hand after the rain.
でも本当は 本当は 本当は 本当に寒いんだ
But the truth is, the truth is, the truth is, it's really cold.
死なない 死なない 僕は何で死なない？
I won't die, I won't die, why won't I die?
夢のひとつも見れないくせに
Even though I can't even see a single dream.
誰も知らない おとぎばなしは
The fairytale nobody knows
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
was absorbed into the sunset and disappeared.
吐き出すような暴力と
Like spitting out violence
蔑んだ目の毎日に
and in every day with looking down eyes,
君はいつしかそこに立っていた
before I knew it, you were standing there.
話しかけちゃだめなのに
Even though you shouldn't talk to me,
「君の名前が知りたいな」
"I want to know your name."
ごめんね 名前も 舌も無いんだ
"I'm sorry, I have no name, nor a tongue."
僕の居場所は 何処にも無いのに
Even though I have no place to belong anywhere,
「一緒に帰ろう」 手を引かれてさ
"Let's go home together," as my hand was pulled.
知らない 知らない 僕は何も知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything,
君はもう子供じゃないことも
even that you are no longer a child.
慣れない他人の手の温もりは
The unfamiliar warmth of another person's hand
ただ本当に 本当に 本当に 本当のことなんだ
is just really, really, really, really the truth.
やめない やめない 君は何でやめない？
Don't stop, don't stop, why won't you stop?
見つかれば殺されちゃうくせに
Even though you'll be killed if they find you.
雨上がりに 忌み子が二人
After the rain, two unwanted children
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
were absorbed into the sunset and disappeared.
日が暮れて 夜が明けて
The sun set, and the night broke,
遊び疲れて 捕まって
tired of playing, we got caught.
こんな世界
In a world like this,
僕と君以外
except for you and me,
皆居なくなればいいのにな
I wish everyone else would just disappear.
知らない 知らない 声が聞こえてさ
I heard an unfamiliar voice,
僕と君以外の 全人類
and all of humanity except you and me,
抗う間もなく 手を引かれてさ
with no time to resist, had their hands pulled,
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
absorbed into the sunset and disappeared.
知らない 知らない 僕は何も知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything,
これからのことも 君の名も
not what's to come, nor even your name.
今は 今は これでいいんだと
But for now, for now, "this is fine,"
ただ本当に 本当に 本当に 本当に思うんだ
is what I truly, truly, truly, truly think.
知らない 知らない あの耳鳴りは
I don't know, I don't know, that ringing in my ears
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
was absorbed into the sunset and disappeared.
風を置いて
Leaving the wind behind,
雨を抜けて
passing through the rain,
咲き誇れ
bloom in full pride!
あぁ、夜風に揺られている
Ah, swaying in the night wind,
折れないように 怯えている
afraid of breaking,
ずっと雨に濡らされている
always getting soaked in the rain,
またどうしたって 凍えてしまったんだ
and frozen up again anyway.
誰か この声に応答して
Someone, respond to this voice.
痛がるばっかで 咲けないままのハートを
With a heart that only feels pain and cannot bloom,
あぁ、今
ah, right now,
見逃せないくらい 綺麗に咲かせたいんだ
I want to make it bloom beautifully so I can't look away.
光っていた未来が
The future that was shining,
ずっと待っていた世界が
the world that was always waiting,
きらめく音の中にあるなら
if it's within the sparkling sound,
最低で最悪な涙も
I want to take along even the worst, most terrible tears,
痛がりで嫌いな声も
and the voice that hates feeling pain,
連れていきたいんだ 全部
I want to take them all.
不完全な毎日が
These incomplete days,
一瞬のカケラたちが 重なって
these pieces of a moment overlap,
こんな歌を奏でたら
and if they play such a song,
それは言葉だけじゃ届かない距離を
it will surely cross the distance that words alone cannot reach,
きっと飛び越えて 結ぶ
and bind them together,
きっと 輪を描いていく
surely, it will draw a circle.
シンコペーションで進む
We move forward with syncopation,
もっともっともっとペースを上げて
faster, faster, faster, picking up the pace!
ペダルを回して 狂うほど回って 飛んでく これじゃ終わらない
Spin the pedals, spin crazily, fly away—it won't end here!
迷ったら踊れ 自堕落なステップでいいさ
If you get lost, dance! Depraved steps are just fine,
お構いなしの稲妻になって
becoming a careless bolt of lightning!
声を枯らせ 泥だらけになってもいい 生きていたい
Scream until your voice is hoarse! Even if we get covered in mud, I want to live!
今夜 あの空で合流して
Let's meet up in that sky tonight,
朝が満ちるまで
until the morning is full!
それぞれの星を探そう
Let's look for our own stars!
ねえ 今 同じこと思っていたんだって ほら
Hey, you know, we were just thinking the exact same thing! Look!
話さなくても分かり合えた
We understood each other without even speaking.
こんな嬉しさをずっと歌ってみたかった
I've always wanted to sing this kind of happiness.
光っていた未来が ずっと待っていた世界が
The glowing future, the world we've been waiting for,
きらめいて目の前にあるから<
because it's glittering right in front of our eyes.
また瞬きの刹那まで このストーリーの最後まで
Until the blink of an eye, until the very end of this story,
輝く花でいたいんだ
I want to be a blooming flower!
不完全な私達が 一瞬の欠片達が
We, who are imperfect, the fragments of a single moment,
重なって今スターマインを奏でてゆくよ
overlapping to play a starmine now!
それは夢見るだけじゃ叶わない思いをずっと
Those feelings that won't come true just by dreaming, forever...
新しくしてゆく ずっと追いかけてゆこう
Renewing them, let's chase them forever!
風を仰いで
Basking in the wind,
雨を抜けて
passing through the rain,
咲き誇れ
bloom in full glory,
何千の空へ
into thousands of skies!
ノンブレス・オブリージュ
[Song: Non-breath oblige]
世界中のすべての人間に好かれるなんて気持ち悪いよ
It's creepy to be liked by everyone in this world.
だけど一つになれない教室で 君と二人 手を繋いでいたいの
But I want to hold hands with you in a classroom where we can't connect.
数の暴力に白旗をあげて
I'll raise the white flag to the tyranny of the majority,
悪感情を殺してハイチーズ
suppress my ill feelings, and say cheese.
ポストトゥルースの甘いディープキス
A sweet, post-truth French kiss,
エロく歪んでるラブアンドピース
a warped, erotic love & peace.
自己中の光線銃 乱射する
A self-centered ray gun, firing wildly,
強者のナンセンス
the nonsense of the strong.
オートクチュールで作る
An haute couture
殺しのライセンス
license to kill.
分断を生んじゃった椅子取りゲーム
A game of musical chairs that created division,
無痛分娩で授かるベイブ
a baby that is given birth by epidural labor.
壮大な内輪ノリを歴史と呼ぶ
We're calling a grandiose in-joke "history."
生きたいが死ねと言われ
I want to live but I'm told to die,
死にたいが生きろと言われ
I want to die but I'm told to live.
生きたいが死ねと言われ
I want to live but I'm told to die,
死にたいが生きろと言われ
I want to die but I'm told to live.
幸せ自慢はダメ？
Is it wrong to boast of my happiness?
不幸嘆いてもダメ？
Is it wrong to grieve over my unhappiness?
図々しい言葉を避け
I'm avoiding impudent words
明るい未来のため
for our glorious future.
さんはい
One, two.
「この世には息もできない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are many people in this world who can't even breathe."
さんはい
One, two.
「この世には息もできない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are many people in this world who can't even breathe."
あちらが立てば こちらが立たず
If I'm true to one side, I'm false to the other;
譲り 奪い 守り 行き違い
we give, we take, we protect, we misunderstand.
地雷原で立ち止まり
I stop in the minefield,
大人しく犬になるんだわ
and obediently become a dog, woof.
ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス オブリージュ
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath oblige.
I love you
息苦しい日々の水面下
Under the surface of my suffocating days,
ゆらゆらと煙る血の花
a flower of blood smokes and flickers.
コンプレックスを武器に争う
We use our complexes as weapons to fight
それぞれの都合と自由のため
for the sake of our convenience and freedom.
息を止めることを強制する
We obligate ourselves to hold our breath.
息が詰まる...
I can't breathe...
生きたいが死ねと言われ
I want to live but I'm told to die,
死にたいが生きろと言われ
I want to die but I'm told to live.
生きたいが死ねと言われ
I want to live but I'm told to die,
死にたいが生きろと言われ
I want to die but I'm told to live.
正当防衛と言ってチェーンソーを振り回す
Saying it's self-defense, wielding a chainsaw,
まともな人たちが怖いよ<
I'm afraid of decent people.
愛燦々 春爛漫
Brilliant love, brilliant spring,
日々だんだん大事なものが消えていくよ
important things are slowly disappearing each and every day.
さんはい
One, two.
「この世には愛も知らない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are many people in this world who don't even know love."
さんはい
One, two.
「この世には愛も知らない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are many people in this world who don't even know love."
共感 羨望 嫉妬 怨嗟
Sympathy, envy, jealousy, resentment,
黒い涙がこぼれ落ち
black tears falling down,
見にくい感情が吹き出し
my ugly emotions burst out
真っ白な鳥になるんだな
and become a snow-white bird.
ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス オブリージュ
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath oblige.
I love you
深海魚と泳ぐ氷点下
Swimming with deep-sea fish below the freezing point,
見上げているザラメの星
looking up at the stars of granulated sugar.
僕らは直接 直接 直接 直接
We don't directly, directly, directly, directly...
手を下さないまま
do anything in person.
想像力を奪う液晶越しに
Through the liquid crystal that robs our imagination,
息の根を止めて安心する
we hold our breaths and feel secure.
ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス オブリージュ
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath oblige.
I love you
それぞれの都合と自由のため
For the sake of our convenience and freedom...
息を止めることを
To hold our breath...
強制する
...is forced upon us.
息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる
I'm suffocating, I'm suffocating, I'm suffocating...
I'm suffocating, I'm suffocating, I'm suffocating!
息を止める 息を止める 息を止める
Hold your breath, hold your breath, hold your breath...
Hold your breath, hold your breath, hold your breath!
ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス・オブリージュ
No breath, no breath, non-breath oblige!
I love you
それぞれの好きを守るため
To protect our respective favorites...
君と防空壕で呼吸する
...I breathe with you in an air-raid shelter.
はぁ、酸素が足りない...
Phew, there's not enough oxygen...
酸素が足りない...
Not enough oxygen...
酸素が足りないんですけど、はい！
I'm literally running out of oxygen, but yes!
続けてやらせていただきました。
I performed those songs back-to-back.
はい、いかがだったでしょうか！
So, how did you like it?!
昨日の配信でも話したんですけど、
I mentioned this in yesterday's stream,
あの、一部人間じゃないやつがあるって言ってたのが、
about some parts being superhuman...
この「ノンブレス・オブリージュ」と、
This "Non-Breath Oblige" and...
さきほどソロでやらせていただいた「ロストワンの号哭」でした！
the song I just performed solo, "The Lost One's Weeping"!
はい！ちょっと...
Yes! Honestly...
純粋にすごく心配だったんですけど、
I was genuinely extremely worried,
なんとかね、歌えてよかったという、
but I'm so relieved I managed to sing them...
今はすごい安心で、今震えております！
that I'm actually trembling with relief right now!
はい！というわけで、ここまでたくさん見ていただきましたが、
Alright! We've come quite far in the live show,
皆さん、いかがですかー？
how is everyone enjoying it?!
ゲストもね、めっちゃ来てもらって、あずきちと、
I had so many amazing guests join me, like Azukichi,
あとミオ先輩、フレア先輩、あと、おかゆ先輩、ねね先輩！
and Mio-senpai, Flare-senpai, Okayu-senpai, and Nene-senpai!
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much!
本当にみんなと歌ってみたい曲を、自分が好きなやつを、
I chose songs that I genuinely wanted to sing with them,
「この人にこれを歌ってるところ聴きたい」っていう気持ちで選んで、
with the feeling of "I really want to hear them sing this,"
一緒にね、やらせていただきました！
and we performed them together!
本当にありがとうございます！先輩たちありがとうー！
Thank you so much! Thank you, senpais!
ふぅ、ちょっと、一回水飲んでもいいですか？
Phew... Can I drink some water for a moment?
水を飲ませてくれ。
Let me have a drink.
はい、よいしょ。はい。
Alright, there we go. Yes.
はい。
Yes.
ちょっと落ち着きました。
I've calmed down a bit now.
はい、ということで、まだまだ続くんでね、
Alright, we still have more to go,
次の曲に行きたいと思うんですけど、
so I'd like to move on to the next song.
次の曲は、昨日のトークでもめっちゃリクエスト上がってて、
As for the next song, there were so many requests in yesterday's talk,
その前からずっとリクエスト上がってて、
and even before that, I've been getting constant requests for it.
「いやこれ生誕ライブにやりたいな」ってことで、
I thought, "Man, I really want to do this for my birthday live,"
ずっととっておいた曲です！
so I've been keeping this song saved up!
なんで楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです。それでは、
So I hope you enjoy it. Now then...
次の曲、聴いてください。ray。
Please listen to the next song: ray.
お別れしたのはもっと 前の事だったような
It feels like our parting was much further in the past...
悲しい光は封じ込めて 踵すり減らしたんだ
I locked away that sad light, wearing down my heels.
うおー
Woah...
君といた時は見えた
I could see it when I was with you...
今は見えなくなった
...but now it's gone out of sight.
透明な彗星をぼんやりと
Vaguely looking for that transparent comet...
でもそれだけ探している
...but that's the only thing I'm searching for.
しょっちゅう唄を歌ったよ
I used to sing songs all the time...
その時だけのメロディーを
...with melodies unique to those moments.
寂しくなんかなかったよ
I wasn't lonely at all...
ちゃんと寂しくなれたから
...because I was able to feel properly lonely.
いつまでどこまでなんて
Wondering how far or how long it would go...
正常か異常かなんて
...or whether it was normal or abnormal.
考える暇も無い程 歩くのは大変だ
Walking is so hard, there's no time to even think about it...
から
...so...
楽しい方がずっといいよ
Being happy is much better.
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll keep on smiling through it all.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
It's alright, that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
...will never disappear even if forgotten.
理想で作った道を
The path made of ideals...
現実が塗り替えていくよ
...is being repainted by reality.
思い出はその軌跡の上で
Our memories, upon those tracks...
輝きになって残っている
...remain, turning into a bright shine.
お別れしたのは何で
Why did we part ways?
何のためだったんだろうな
What was it all for, I wonder?
悲しい光が
The sad light...
悲しい光が僕の影を
The sad light is stretching my shadow...
前に長く伸ばしている
...out long in front of me.
時々熱が出るよ
Sometimes I get a fever,
時間がある時眠るよ
and sleep when I have time.
夢だと解るその中で
Inside that dream where I know it's a dream,
君と会ってからまた行こう
let's meet you, then keep going.
晴天とはほど遠い
Far from a clear blue sky,
終わらない暗闇にも
in the endless darkness,
星を思い浮かべたなら
if I picture the stars in my mind,
すぐ銀河の中だ
I'm already in the middle of the galaxy.
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry as much anymore,
靴を新しくしても
and even if I get new shoes,
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
it's okay, that pain
忘れたって消えやしない
won't disappear even if I forget it.
伝えたかった事がきっとあったんだろうな
There must have been something I wanted to tell you.
恐らくありきたりなんだろうけど こんなにも
It's probably cliché, but I feel it this much.
お別れした事は
The fact that we parted
出会った事と繋がっている
is connected to the fact that we met.
あの透明な彗星は
That transparent comet
透明だから無くならない
won't disappear because it's transparent.
◯×どれかなんて
Checking to see if it's a circle or an X,
皆と比べてどうかなんて保存
or how I compare to everyone else...
確かめる間も無いほど
I'm so busy living
生きるのは最高だ
I don't have time to check; it's the best.
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry as much anymore,
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll gloss over it and keep laughing.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは保存
It's okay, that pain
忘れたって消えやしない
won't disappear even if I forget it.
大丈夫だ この光の
It's okay, because in the beginning
始まりには君がいる
of this light, you are here.
はい！ということで、rayでしたー！
Okay! So, that was 'ray'!
あー、どうだったですか？
Ah, how was it?
めっちゃエモい、エモい、感じになりましたね。はい！
It became a very emotional, emotional feeling. Yes!
ちょっと一瞬水飲んでいいですか？
Can I drink some water for a second?
水、水が...
Water, water...
うん、お、え
Yeah, oh, eh...
あ、ごめん
Ah, sorry.
飲んでも飲んでも減らない水、いいだろ。風真いろは特注だぜ。
Water that doesn't decrease no matter how much you drink, nice right? It's a Kazama Iroha custom edition.
よいしょ、ちょっと待って
Up we go, wait a second...
おし、はい
Alright, yes.
というわけで、次の曲に行きたいと思うんですけど、
So, I'd like to move on to the next song, but...
あの、昨日のうた枠でちょっと匂わせしたんですが、本番ですね、
Um, I hinted at it a bit during yesterday's singing stream, but this is the real deal.
あの、視聴者参加型3D生ライブになっておりまして、はい、
This is an audience-participation style 3D live concert! Yes!
今回はですね、皆さんに投票をしていただいて、次に歌う曲決めたいと思います！
So this time, I'd like you all to vote to decide the next song I sing!
なんじゃそりゃって思うかもしれないんですけど、視聴者参加型曲決め合戦ってことです！
You might be wondering what that is, but it's an audience-participation song-selection battle!
それでは、テロップどうぞ！
So, cue the graphic!
じゃじゃーん！
Tada!
ええ、ANIMAかただ声一つ、どっちか！
Either 'ANIMA' or 'Tada Koe Hitotsu', which one?!
で、投票が少なかった方も、この後メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブで歌いますので、
And whichever song gets fewer votes will be sung later during the membership-only encore stream,
よろしくお願いします！いや、どちらも名曲で、迷いますよね。
so please look forward to it! Gosh, both are great songs, so it's a hard choice.
今、スタッフの人とどっちになるかねっていうのを賭けてます！
Right now, I'm making a bet with the staff on which one it'll be!
あの、どっちに賭けてるかは言わないんで、さあ、みんな、これで次回の差し入れが豪華になるか、裏で決まるからな！はい！
I won't say which one I bet on, but everyone, this will decide behind the scenes whether my next catering will be fancy or not! Yes!
というわけで、早速投票を開始していきたいと思います！大体時間は1分ぐらいですかね？
So, I'd like to start the voting right away! We have about one minute, right?
それでは、よーい、スタート！
Alright, ready... start!
届いた？
Did it go through?
今、来たかな？
Is it coming now?
お、たくさん来た来た。来た来た、来た。
Oh, a lot of them are coming! They're coming!
はい、じゃあみんな、投票ボタン押してね。
Alright, everyone, press the voting button!
じゃあみんなが投票やってる間に、ゆっくりみんなのこと待つために帰るわ、メインステージ。
Well, while everyone is voting, I'll head back to the main stage to slowly wait for you guys.
じゃ、移動ですよ。移動〜。
Well, time to move. Moving~!
はい、というわけで、皆さん、
Alright, so, everyone...
投票した？できてる？
did you vote? Are you able to?
どっちかだよ。
Choose one of them.
両方はちょっとあれだから、どっちかに、どっちかにお願いします。
Both is a bit... so please choose one of them.
そういえば今、なんだかんだ言って歩かせてもらってますが、
By the way, I'm walking right now, but...
実はね、なにげにね、
actually, you see...
ファーストミッション衣装がね、
this first mission outfit...
見せるのが、ゆっくり見せるのが、初めてだったりするんだけど...
showing it, showing it slowly, might actually be the first time...
そうだ、ここで、ここでさ、宣伝しとこう。尺稼ぎじゃないよ！あの、宣伝ね！
That's right, let's promote it here. This isn't just to buy time! It's a promotion!
このあとメインでアフターライブがあるんですけど、
After this, we have the After Live on the main stage, and...
その時の時にもっと、このかっこいいところをね、いっぱい見せますので、
at that time, I will show you a lot of these cool parts.
なんでぜひよかったらメンゲンのアフターライブにもお越しください！っていう宣伝も入れつつ、
So please come to the members-only After Live if you'd like! Adding that promotion...
みんな入れた？もう入れた？
Did everyone vote? Did you vote already?
でもすごいな、この花道。長くない？
But this runway is amazing. Isn't it long?
な、長くない？
I-Isn't it long?
これ、これ現地ライブでもやりたいな。
I want to do this at a venue live too.
はい、もうだいぶかっこいい風真いろはをいっぱい見せているわけなんですが、
Yes, I'm showing a lot of cool Kaza Iroha already...
いや、でもどっちかな？これ。
but which one will it be?
ANIMAはね、みんな、設定の通りあの、かっこいい、かっこいいで、
With ANIMA, as per the settings, it's cool and badass.
「ただ声一つ」はしっとり、しっとり、なんでね。これ好みが分かれると思いますが。
While "Tada Koe Hitotsu" is quiet and emotional. I think preferences will be split.
はい、いやきっとね、どっちやってもみんなかっこいいって言ってくれるよね。
But I'm sure whichever it is, everyone will say it's cool.
言ってくれるよね？
You'll say it, right?
え、言って、言ってくれる？お、言ってくれる、言ってくれる。
Oh, you will? Ah, you will, you will.
カメラは言ってくれるってことで。はい、というわけで、みんな、もう大丈夫かな？
The camera says yes. Alright, so, is everyone ready?
おっけー？
Okay?
じゃあそろそろ終わっちゃいますからね。
Then we'll be closing the poll soon.
はい、早く早く、早く投票してね！
Hurry, hurry! Vote quickly!
お？終わった？終わったんだよね？スタッフさん。
Oh? Is it over? It's over, right, staff?
終わった？
Is it over?
早かった？歩くの。
Was my walking fast?
終わった？終わった、おわ、終わったかな？
Is it over? Is it over?
あ。
Ah.
あ、終わったらしい！
Oh, looks like it's over!
今、かけをしているスタッフとにらめっこしてます。
Right now, I'm having a staring contest with the staff who made a bet.
それでは、
And now...
結果発表タイム！
it's time to announce the results!
ドゥルルルルルルルル...
Drumroll...
バン！
Bam!
アンケートの結果、ANIMAになったみたいです！
Based on the poll results, it looks like it's ANIMA!
あ、これあの、かけに勝った人の動きです。
Ah, this is the movement of someone who won the bet.
ういー、それでは期待してます。よっしゃー！
Yes! I'm looking forward to it. All right!
というわけで、かけにも勝ち、皆さんにも選んでいただき、とてもありがたい限りですね。
So, I won the bet and got chosen by all of you, I'm very grateful.
あの「ただ声一つ」の方もこのあとメンバーシップ限定で歌いますので、そちらもお楽しみに。
I'll also sing "Tada Koe Hitotsu" during the members-only stream later, so look forward to that too.
というわけで、
With that said...
早速歌っていきましょうか。
let's get right into singing.
それでは聞いてください。ANIMA。
Please listen to it: ANIMA.
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the color of the soul?
「もういっそ 折れたままで」
"Might as well, just stay broken"
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど
I'm not strong enough to throw it away,
強くないよ ほら
to run away, look.
もう一度
Once more...
鼓動、高鳴る
Once more, my heartbeat accelerates.
何が正しいかなんて
I don't know what is correct,
わからないけど
but...
形のないものばかりが
only things without form
大切になって行く
are becoming precious to me.
飾らない言葉だけが
Only unadorned words
強く結ばれてる
are strongly connected.
また躓いて 転がって
I stumble and fall again,
それでも砕けない
but it won't break.
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the color of the soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって保存
I'm just hurt, I'm just faking strength,
それでも見つけたいよ
but I still want to find it,
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I'm confirming the form of my soul.
深い地の底で一人
Alone in the depths of the earth,
扉と鍵を探す
I search for a door and a key.
おとぎ話は ほら
The fairy tale, look,
泡の様に全部消えて
it all disappears like bubbles.
葛藤 残像だけ
Only conflicts and afterimages...
次の頁へ
...go to the next page.
...て
...ing,
それぞれの道を行く
Each walks their own path.
寂しい思い出だけが
Only lonely memories
強く根を張ってる
are deeply rooted.
まだ
Still,
貫いて失って それでも挫けない
even so, piercing and losing, I won't crumble.
心はどこに
Where is the heart?
器はどこに
Where is the vessel?
ただ
Just,
残されて抜け落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
being left behind, falling out, even so, I want to convey
魂の日々を
the days of the soul,
魂の意志を
the will of the soul,
ずっと
always...
魂の色は
What color is the color of your soul?
何色ですか
What color is it?
赤色ですか
Is it red?
青色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
What color is the color of your soul?
何色ですか
What color is it?
透明な過去に
In a transparent past,
不透明な明日に
in an opaque tomorrow,
生きるあなたは
you who are living,
何色ですか
what color are you?
まだ
Still,
躓いて 転がって それでも砕けない
stumbling again, rolling over, even so, it doesn't break.
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the color of your soul?
ただ
Just,
傷ついて 強がって それでも見つけたいよ
getting hurt, acting tough, even so, I want to find it.
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I'm confirming the shape of my soul,
ずっと
always...
はい！ということで、ANIMAを歌わせていただきました！
Yes! And with that, I sang ANIMA!
カロリー高いほうだったな。水、水ください。
That song really burned a lot of calories. Water, please give me some water.
カロリー高いほうだった。危ない。
That was a high-calorie song. So close.
あ、すいません。あの、ナチュラルにマイクを返すの忘れていました。
Ah, sorry. I naturally forgot to hand back the microphone.
やばい、音変になってなかったらいいな。すいません。
Oh dear, I hope the audio didn't sound weird. My apologies.
ナチュラルに。スタッフさんがすっごい手伸ばしてくれてたのに、疲れすぎてここ硬直してた。
Just naturally... The staff member was stretching their hand out so much, but I was so tired that I just froze up here.
はい。水うまい。
Alright. This water is delicious.
減らない水のおかげで生きていけてます。はい。
I'm surviving thanks to this bottomless water. Yes.
じゃあ、ちょっとこれ返して。
Well, let me hand this back.
はい。それではですね、ちょっと、まだまだ続くんですけど、
Okay. Now then, there's still more to come, but...
ここいらで一旦、重大告知タイムをさせていただきたいと思います！
Right about now, I'd like to take a moment for some major announcements!
じゃ、まずはいつものから行くか！じゃ、まずは、こちら！
Well, shall we start with the usual? First up is this!
風真いろは誕生日記念グッズ2026出ます！ドンドコドンドン！
Kazama Iroha Birthday Commemorative Merchandise 2026 is coming out! *drumroll*!
いやあ、なんか良さそうなラインナップですね。
Wow, it looks like a really great lineup!
はい、今回もとってもこだわったグッズばかりなんで、皆さん楽しみにしていてほしいです！
Yes, once again these are items we put a lot of care into, so I hope everyone looks forward to them!
では、1つずつ商品を見ていきましょう。まずは、こちら！
Now, let's take a look at each item one by one. First, this!
タペストリーが出ます！
A tapestry is coming out!
タペストリー、実は個人グッズで出すの、超久しぶりなんですよね。
It's actually been a very long time since I released a tapestry as part of my solo merch.
イラストは、もちぷよ先生描き下ろしで、雨上がりの青空の下で、本当にね、このステージみたいな感じで、あの、ライブをしている風真いろはのイメージで描いていただきました。ありがとうございます！
The illustration is newly drawn by Mochipuyo-sensei. It shows Kazama Iroha performing a live show under a blue sky after the rain, with a stage vibe just like this one. Thank you so much!
いや、めっちゃいいよね。飾ってね。
Wow, it's really nice, isn't it? Please display it!
続いてはこちら。フード付きタオル！
Next is this: a hooded towel!
はい、タペストリーと同じイラストのフード付きタオルです。フード部分はぽこべぇの顔になっており、取り外しが可能となっております。
Yes, it's a hooded towel featuring the same illustration as the tapestry. The hood is shaped like Pokobe's face and is detachable.
出すんで、あの、これでぽこべえごっこができるようになります。ぽこべえごっこをしたい方、
Since it comes off, you can use this to pretend to be Pokobei. Those who want to pretend to be Pokobei...
まあ取り外してそのまま飾りたい方もね、どうぞ。
or if you just want to take it off and display it, go ahead.
はい、そしてお次はこちら！
Okay! And next up is this!
ペットボトルホルダー！
Plastic bottle holder!
あの、これは風真いろはさんが欲しいのつく、作りました。
I made this because it's something I wanted myself.
あの、イラストはさめあんこ先生に描いていただきました。可愛いでしょ？
The illustration was drawn by Sameanko-sensei. Isn't it cute?
この真ん中の穴に、あの、ぎゅってペットボトルのところを入れてね、あの...
You squeeze the neck of the plastic bottle into this center hole...
使うやつです。はい、めちゃめちゃおしゃれです。よかったら使ってください。
and that's how you use it. Yes, it's super stylish. Please use it if you'd like.
カバンとかね、つけて持ち運べるんでね、はい。
You can attach it to your bag or something to carry it around, yes.
はい。そしてラストはこちら！
Okay. And the last one is this!
はい！
Yes!
実は地味になかった、セーラー服版の風真いろはのぬいぐるみ！なんと、ボイス付きです！
A plushie of Kazama Iroha in her sailor uniform, which didn't exist until now! And surprisingly, it has voices!
こちらもさめあんこ先生に原案考えていただきました。レインポンチョを着た、
Sameanko-sensei also designed the concept for this. It's a plushie wearing a rain poncho...
声が出るぬいぐるみです。
that plays voices.
まあ、あの、お腹をにぎにぎすると音が出るらしいぞ。
Apparently, it makes a sound when you squeeze its tummy.
今のところはな。はい。外出時にカバンなどにつけることもできます。で、ボイスなんですけど、
At least for now. Yes. You can also attach it to your bag when you go out. As for the voices,
なんか天気に関するものを録ったんですよ。どんな感じかはまださすがに言えないけど、
I recorded lines related to the weather. I can't tell you exactly what they are yet, but...
だけど、あの、おみくじ感覚で聞いて、その天気にならなかったからといって、
please listen to it like a fortune cookie, and even if the weather doesn't turn out like that,
風真いろはを責めないでください。自己責任で、にぎにぎしてください。
please don't blame Kazama Iroha. Squeeze it at your own risk.
買ってからのお楽しみです！いっぱいありましたが、フルセット見ていきましょう！
It's a surprise for after you buy it! We have a lot, but let's take a look at the full set!
こちら！
Here it is!
今回のグッズはですね、生誕のイメージに合わせてフェス風をテーマに作ってみました。
For this merchandise, we went with a festival theme to match the image of my birthday.
実用性たっぷりだし、これからの季節にぴったりなんで、よかったらよろしくお願いします。
They're highly practical and perfect for the upcoming season, so please check them out.
そして、フルセット購入特典は、こちら！
And here is the bonus for purchasing the full set!
数量限定版あります。風真いろはの直筆サインと、箔押し複製メッセージ入り、
We have a limited-quantity edition. It features Kazama Iroha's handwritten signature and a foil-stamped message...
チケット風カード。ちょっとおしゃれな感じですね。
on a ticket-style card. It feels quite stylish, doesn't it?
そして通常版には、箔押し複製サインとメッセージ入りチケット風カードがついてきます。
And the standard edition comes with a foil-stamped signature and ticket-style card with a message.
えー、さらにどちらにも、えー、ボイスがついてきますね、はい。
And both editions also come with a voice recording. Yes.
「君と雨宿り」というなんかタイトルのボイスがついてくるんですけど、まあ、ぶっちゃけあの、
It comes with a voice track titled "Sheltering from the Rain with You," but honestly,
気になったら聞いてください。
if you're curious, please listen to it.
ボイスは、めっちゃ頑張って撮ったからね！
I worked really hard on recording the voice track, you know!
はい。ということで、シチュエーションボイスですね。雨宿り系だった気が、なんか照れながら撮った気がします。
Yes, so it's a situation voice. I think it was a rain-sheltering theme, and I recorded it while being super embarrassed.
そして、グッズは21時カートオープンです。すみません、あの、
And the merchandise cart opens at 21:00. I'm sorry,
生配信につき、ちょっと時間が押しそうなんですけど、あの、
since this is a live stream, we might run slightly over time, but...
ゆっくり買ってね、とは言えず、頑張ってください。何とも言いようがない、ごめん。
I can't tell you to take your time buying, so please do your best. There's no other way to say it, sorry.
そしてあの、21時からホロカート多分配信控えてると思うんですけど、あの、何も気にしなくていいんでスタートしてくださいね。
Also, HoloCart is probably scheduled to stream at 21:00, but please don't worry about us and just go ahead and start.
はい！
Yes!
そして、まだまだあります。まだまだ。それが、こちら！
And there is even more! More! And that is this!
はい！新曲！いえーーい！
Yes! A new song! Yay!
風真いろはさん、新曲が出ます。タイトルは「風向きエントロピー」！
Kazama Iroha will release a new song. The title is "Kazamuki Entropy"!
作詞・作曲は「いろはステップ」でもおなじみ、40mPさんにしていただきました！
It was written and composed by 40mP, who is also known for "Iroha Step"!
はい、配信後にこちらMVが、えーと、公開されます。多分こっそり今マネちゃんがプレミア公開に切り替えてくれているはず。
Yes, the music video will be released after this stream. My manager is probably covertly switching it to a premiere right now.
楽曲は0時リリースになっております！
The digital release of the song will be at midnight!
はい、そして、あの、ちょっと気づいた人もいるかもしれないんですけど、ジャケットの文字は風真いろはさんが自分で書きました。はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes. And as some of you might have noticed, the title text on the jacket cover was handwritten by me. Yes, thank you very much.
ということで、もう終わっちゃうんですけど、なんかすごいトレンド2位とかに入ってるっていう連絡を受けました。くそ！
So, it's already ending, but I just received word that we reached #2 in the trends! Shoot!
あと残り、頑張ってくれ、と言いたいけど、でも、みんな本当にいっぱいポストしてくれてありがとうね。
I want to tell you to keep going, but really, thank you so much for posting so much, everyone.
よし、準備できた？大人の準備は全部できてそうなので、
Alright, are you ready? It seems like all the staff preparations are complete, so...
早速、新曲、歌っていきたいと思います！
without further ado, I'd like to sing my new song!
しかし、今回はちょっと特別なものを用意してきました！
However, I've prepared something special for today!
ゴンドラ！来い！
Gondola! Come on out!
おおー！リハーサルで見たけどやっぱりいいな、これ！
Oh! I saw it during rehearsals, but this is indeed awesome!
ほい！
There!
というわけで、みんな、ぽこべえがいなくて寂しかったでしょ？今年は...ゴンドラになりました！
So, everyone, you missed Pokobei, didn't you? This year... he became a gondola!
はい、というわけで、早速やっていくんですが、
Yes, and so we will start right away,
ドア、オープン！
Door, open!
いぇーい！ほっ！よいしょっと！
Yay! Ho! Up we go!
というわけで、早速歌っていきたいと思います！
And so, I would like to sing right away!
それでは聴いてください。風真いろは、新オリジナル曲「風向きエントロピー」！
Now please listen. Kazama Iroha's new original song, "Kazamuki Entropy"!
ねえ いつからそこにいたの？
Hey, since when have you been there?
あまりにも近くて気づかなかったよ
You were so close that I didn't even notice.
ずっと私が生まれた日から
Ever since the day I was born,
そばにいてくれたのにね
even though you've always been by my side.
曖昧で複雑で
Vague, complex,
予測不可能で
and unpredictable...
想像していた
I had imagined...
その染まった世に
into that stained world,
うまく笑えない
I cannot smile properly.
だけどそれ以上に
But even more than that,
世界は優しくて
the world is so kind.
いつか風が生まれた
Someday, a wind was born.
足跡が始まる場所
The place where footprints begin.
あの日の荷物持って 帰って
Carrying the baggage of that day, I return.
駆け出したとしても ここに来るんだろう
Even if I ran out, I would probably end up here.
この景色も この声も
This scenery, this voice,
私を彩る全て
everything that colors me.
本音なんて まだわからないけど
Though I still don't know my true feelings,
ただ風の吹くままに
I'll just go as the wind blows.
ねぇ いつから気づいてたの？
Hey, since when did you notice?
まるで私のこと全部お見通しで
It's like you saw right through me.
苦し紛れにごまかした嘘も
Even the lies I used to scramble by...
君にはバレてたのかな？
Did you see right through those too?
平凡で退屈であくび混じりで
Ordinary, boring, and mixed with yawns,
変哲のないありふれている時間
those completely mundane moments.
想像していただけじゃ何も変わらない
Just imagining things changes nothing.
だけどそれ以上に
But even more than that,
予測してた以上に ほら
even more than I expected, look!
新しい風が吹いてきて
A new wind starts to blow.
不器用な自分がやけに愛おしく思えたんだ
My clumsy self felt strangely endearing to me.
あぁ
Ah...
いつか風が止んで
Someday, the wind will stop,
足跡が途切れた場所
at the place where the footprints fade.
落とし物探して 拾って 見つけ出せたから
Searching for lost things, picking them up, because I found them...
ここにいるんだろう
I am probably here.
そっと 髪がなびく
Softly, my hair flutters.
いつか風が夢見た
Someday, the wind dreamed
青空と交わる場所
of the place where it meets the blue sky.
回り道選んで 迷って つまずいたとしても
Even if I choose detours, get lost, and stumble,
そこへ行くんだろう
I will go there.
この景色も この声も
This scenery, this voice,
私を彩る全て
everything that colors me.
等身大の手で握りしめて
I'll hold it tight with my true self.
想像以上にもっと自由な速度で
At a pace even more free than imagined.
方向なんてまだわからないけど
I still don't know the direction yet,
ただ風の吹くままに
but I'll just go as the wind blows.
はい！というわけでありがとうございました！
Yes! So, thank you very much!
よいしょ。みんなしっかり忘れてると思うけど、今日これから記念撮影します！
Up we go. I'm sure you all completely forgot, but we're going to take a commemorative photo now!
そう、お土産があるって言ったっしょ？
That's right, I told you there would be a souvenir, right?
これこれ、あ、ちょっと待って、マジで自撮り棒…これリハーサルでめっちゃ練習したのに…
Here it is. Ah, wait a minute, seriously, this selfie stick... even though I practiced so much in rehearsal...
自撮り棒下手…あ、いい感じいい感じ。カシャ。
I'm so bad at using selfie sticks... Oh, this looks good. Click!
よし、いけてそういけてそう。オッケー！
Alright, looks like it worked. Okay!
はい！というわけで、みなさん、今日お土産ありって言いましたね？
Yes! So, everyone, I did say there would be a souvenir today, right?
そうなんです。今日撮った、今この風真がね、自撮り棒で撮った写真が…
That's right. The photo I just took with the selfie stick...
コンビニで！なんとプリントアウトできます！すすごい！
Can actually be printed out at convenience stores! Wow!
はい。こちらですね、対象店舗、ファミリーマートさん、ローソンさん、ミニストップさんで
Yes. It's available at participating FamilyMart, Lawson, and Ministop stores,
本日21時から、えーネットで事前購入ができます。
and you can purchase it online starting at 9 PM today.
お値段がですね、税込み300円とのことでの。
The price is 300 yen (tax included).
印刷できるのは、えー明日の6月19日、えー20時までとなっております。
You can print it out until tomorrow, June 19th, at 8 PM.
写真にはですね、複製手書きメッセージ、あのこの後書きますんで、はい。
And yes, I'll write a replica handwritten message on the photo after this.
どんな写真が撮れているか、ちょっと写真下手くそでも怒らないでね？
Please don't be mad if I'm bad at taking photos, okay?
あの内容は買ってから確認してください。
Please check the content after you buy it.
いや凄いよね。ちょっといち早く皆さんの元に、なんか手元に残るライブのね、お土産が用意できればということで
Isn't that great? I wanted to quickly provide you all with a tangible souvenir from the live,
今回やらせていただきました。お土産あります！
which is why we decided to do this. We have souvenirs!
ちょっと皆さん 各自で回収って形で それだけが申し訳ないんですが お土産ありますんで
I'm sorry that you'll have to go collect it yourselves, but I have a souvenir for you,
ぜひ気になったら コンビニでプリントしてみてください！
so if you're interested, please try printing it at a convenience store!
そして コンビニプリント購入できるのは 7月21日 17時59分までです
Also, the convenience store prints are available until July 21st at 5:59 PM.
概要欄に 写真購入のリンク 多分今マネちゃんがやってくれていると思いますので よろしくお願いします！
I think Manager-chan is putting the link to purchase the photo in the description right now, so please check it out!
そして この後はですね MVの公開と メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブありますので
And after this, we'll have the MV premiere and the membership-exclusive encore live,
そちらも絶対に聴いてくださいね！
so please be sure to tune in to those as well!
それでは 皆様 またお会いしましょう！
Well then, everyone, see you again!
最高の誕生日でした！バイバーイ！
It was the best birthday ever! Bye-bye!